

# **SM Mashuque**

Interested in Software Development.



# **Summary**

Determined to become a Software Engineer. Excited to build things with programming. Have experience working with APIs and Django framework from last internship. Currently, I am learning and building small projects with Django as the backend and React as the frontend. Learning new things about software design is very exciting to me. I am always exploring and expanding my understanding of important concepts and best practices in programming.



# **Education**

08-2016 -05-2020

### Cornell University, B.S. in Information Science

- Major GPA: 3.5 | Cumulative GPA: 3.4
- Relevant courses taken include 00 Programming in Python, Data Structures in Java, Backend Web Development in PHP, Systems Programming in C/C++, and Data Science in Python.



# **Experience**

08-2018 present

#### Teaching Assistant in Web Design Course

Cornell University

Led weekly discussion sections and answered questions relating to HTML,
CSS, and JavaScript in the intro web design course. Met with the professor weekly and helped grade assignments.

06-2018 -08-2018

#### Software Engineer Intern

SinglePlatform

- Django MVC: Updated existing models, views, templates, and wrote unit tests.
- Created an API endpoint with pagination for restaurant locations, menus, and photos data using Django REST framework.
- Created asynchronous tasks to update models, and send emails using Celery and SendGrid.
- · Applied view restrictions with Python decorators.
- Created a GUI app in Python for internal use to automate schedule creation process using Google Calendar API.

08-2017 -05-2018

#### Python Tutor

Cornell University

 Met with CS 1110 course students weekly and provided assistance with Python questions relating to homework, assignments, and exams.

07-2015 -08-2015

#### **QA** Intern

SinglePlatform

 Fixed website presentation bugs. Addressed and fixed technical debt issues. Worked on improving unit test coverage.



# **Personal Projects**

Built a web app to show live stock price information for Nasdaq companies.

- Integrated the app with IEX API for showing latest stock price information.
- Built a React frontend that calls the Django backend and IEX API to update the data every second on client side without page reload.
- · Learned to deploy in Heroku.

Built a Breakout game in JavaScript.



#### **Phone**

347-694-9301

#### E-mail

smjim1998@gmail.com

#### **Website**

https://smmashuq.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/smmashuq/



Python

Django

C++

••••

Java

React

JavaScript

••••

PHP

NumPy

mySQL

Android

